# Karen Ma

## karenma.me | karenma333@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/karenma333

### Summary

Skills Product Strategy | Requirements Gathering | User Research | Technical Design |

Qualitative Ethnography | User Testing | Web Analytics | User Experience Design

Software | Axure | Adobe XD | Figma | Sketch | Google Analytics | Looker

## **Experience**

NextCapital — Lead Designer

Previously: Full Stack Product Designer

Sept 2019 - Present Oct 2018 - Sept 2019

- Led the product design and development of a new feature to increase the size of existing user base by 68% and increase the new user aggregation rate by 5x
- Drove the redesign of the primary product into a new design system by aligning team members on scope, conducting design reviews and critiques, engaging with key stakeholders in the design process
- Defined new guidelines, from content strategy to interaction patterns to create a design system on top of the existing visual design library
- Evangelized the usage of user research in the product development process, using tools such as SurveyMonkey, UsabilityHub, in-person moderated user testing sessions
- Building out a web analytics foundation for design and product to measure success of features and review usability issues, using data analytics software, Looker, Segment and built-in Google Analytics.
- Improved the design/developer relationship through guidelines on expected artifacts and new pairing processes
- Shaped design culture through design and people mentorship, hosting quarterly educational presentations to increase junior designer knowledge base and provide continuing education opportunities

Design4SD — Research Assistant

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

I worked in the UCSD Design Lab under Steven Dow and Narges Mayhar working on investigating better ways to encourage and promote participatory design when it comes to civic design challenges. Check out the current status of the project here - https://d4sd.org/.

- Contributed to secondary research by reading existing literature on solutions and their shortcomings
- Conducted interviews with stakeholders in current mobility projects in Downtown San Diego as well as with leaders of civic engagement workshops in San Diego
- Prototyped a civic engagement process design involving mentoring student groups to solve mobility challenges.

#### Education

University of California, San Diego BS Cognitive Science (Human Computer Interaction) — 2018 Minor: Computer Science

#### **Activities**

Industry Advisor - America Needs You

June 2020 - Sept 2020